Vinícius de Melo Carvalho

Brazilian, 27 years old Rua Capote Valente, 234, Ap. 41, 05409-000 – Pinheiros, São Paulo, SP, Brazil vmcarva@gmail.com, Mobile: + 55 11 94503 4164

SHORT PROFILE

More than 5 years of experience in IT projects with a Master degree in Information Systems at the University of Münster, Germany. Led system development projects, bridging tech and business teams in Brazil, from requirements analysis, to development, testing and deployment of systems in production environment. International experience of 3 years in Germany for studies and internship in IT Risk Management, performing data analysis and reporting. Master Thesis on Digital Humans, at the Digital Disruption Research Group of the University of Sydney, in Australia. Interested in working in analytics, big data, data science and artificial intelligence projects.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Knowledge of Python programming (Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, SciPy), statistics, dataset cleaning and manipulation for data analysis
- Creation of SQL queries (MS SQL Server e MySQL), data modeling and database creation for relational databases, and dimensional databases for Business Intelligence
- Experience with Git for version control and source code management
- Advanced Excel, programming with VBA and strong analytical and reporting skills, with a keen eye
 for detail.
- Experienced in requirements analysis and software design, with the ability to identify strategic and cost-effective solutions to ensure optimal project delivery.
- Experienced in project management best practices and agile methodologies for systems development, managing multiple projects simultaneously.
- Strong written and verbal communication skills. Fluent in English, with experience in multicultural environments, reporting and negotiating with external parties and other stakeholders.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Volkswagen AG, Wolfsburg, Germany (Industry: Automotive) 03/2017 – 09/2017

IT Strategy, Risk and Compliance Intern: Designed, developed and optimized SQL, Excel and VBA data analysis and reports for IT Risk management, project controlling, communication measures, presentation documents, and other analyses. Designed, developed, and optimized SQL, Excel and VBA reports for the Annual GRC Reporting and Quarterly Risk Reporting process. Tracked, forecasted and performed data reporting about key metrics, such as the evolution of users and roles, risks and countermeasures in the IT Risk Management system. Supported project managers in communicating with global stakeholders in other countries. Updated IT Risk Management system data dictionary and IT Risk Evaluation Tool user manual.

Itaú Unibanco Bank, São Paulo, Brazil (Industry: Banking) 03/2012 - 04/2015

Systems Analyst: Successfully led project development activities in respect to Credit Risk Systems for the Itau Unibanco corporate investment bank. Performed engineering and project management activities,

coordinating with product owner and banking areas. Carried out detailed project planning, project execution and source configuration activities, working closely with outsourcing software partner. Performed data modeling, object maintenance and data manipulation of the system database to elicit requirements, develop and test user demands. Executed unit, integration and functional tests in order to meet the quality criteria of several areas, such as product owners, banking users, Change Management and Production. Prepared and managed Build and Deploy Plans in development, test, acceptance and production environments.

IT Intern: Rewrote legacy database objects in SQL Server 2008. Created and updated existing Data Models, Functional and Technical Specifications, Business Flow Diagrams, Functional Test Plans, and System Manuals. Elaborated initial size and estimated time of projects. Developed weekly reports on projects and demands on Excel and VBA.

Conquest One Consulting, São Paulo, Brazil (Industry: Consulting) 05/2010 - 10/2011**Bilingual Service Desk Analyst:**

- Customer/ Project: Oracle and B2W Digital E-Commerce
 - Provided single point of contact and support for databases and weblogic servers, managing service requests, incidents, problems, and changes using ASK tool. Created operational processes and solutions for the Service Desk activities.
- **Customer/ Project:** Walmart Brasil

Provided single point of contact and support for users on service requests and incidents using Remedy tool. Used Remote Access to troubleshoot routine technical systems issues, such as Windows, Microsoft Office, Active Directory, and VPN.

EDUCATION

University of Münster, Germany Information Systems, Master Degree 04/2016 - 07/2019

The University of Sydney Business School, Australia Visiting Scholar – Digital Disruption Research Group

10/2018 - 02/2019

01/2011 - 07/2015

São Paulo State Technological College (FATEC)

Systems Analysis and Development, Bachelor Degree

SPECIFIC SKILLS

- Basic knowledge of HTML, CSS, Angular and Typescript, .NET and Visual Studio
- Notions of Cloud Computing with Google Cloud Services
- Experience in using PMBOK Project Management and SCRUM for agile software development
- ITIL v3 Certified, with previous experiences in Incident, Problem and Change Management
- Experience with IT Risk Management and the routine of an IT Risk Management Office
- Basic knowledge of COBIT
- Experienced IBM Rational Team Concert for Application Lifecycle Management, Source Configuration Management, Build and Deploy

LANGUAGES

- Full English proficiency
- Advanced German proficiency C1 level
- Intermediate Spanish proficiency B1 level
- Native Portuguese speaker